<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="es"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.4.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://jacobosucari.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><link href="http://jacobosucari.com/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="es"/><updated>2025-05-06T16:55:09+00:00</updated><id>http://jacobosucari.com/feed.xml</id><subtitle>A simple, whitespace theme for academics. Based on [*folio](https://github.com/bogoli/-folio) design. </subtitle><entry><title type="html">Walter Benjamin, the aura of the road</title><link href="http://jacobosucari.com/blog/2025/walter-benjamin-in-english/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Walter Benjamin, the aura of the road"/><published>2025-05-06T11:59:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-05-06T11:59:00+00:00</updated><id>http://jacobosucari.com/blog/2025/walter-benjamin-in-english</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://jacobosucari.com/blog/2025/walter-benjamin-in-english/"><![CDATA[<p>Download technical specifications <a href="/assets/pdf/walter-benjamin.pdf">here</a> (in English)</p> <h2 id="synopsis">Synopsis</h2> <p>The philosopher Walter Benjamin attempted to flee the Nazi advance in 1940 by crossing the border between France and Spain on foot. His escape ended in suicide. The route he took between Banyuls and Portbou has since been named the Walter Benjamin Trail, and is traveled every year by hundreds of pilgrims who come to honor his memory along with that of other exiles: those of the Republican side after Franco’s coup in Spain, and those fleeing Nazi barbarism in World War II. The documentary “Walter Benjamin, the aura of the road” is the story of this route, a tale of historical memory, a reflection on exile and Benjamin’s thinking.</p> <iframe src="https://player.vimeo.com/video/954134740" width="700" height="480" frameborder="0" webkitallowfullscreen="" mozallowfullscreen="" allowfullscreen=""> </iframe> <h2 id="technical-specifications">Technical specifications</h2> <ul> <li>Direction and production: Jacobo Sucari</li> <li>Reading of Walter Benjamin’s texts: Dominique Delpirou</li> <li>Voice-over narrator: Rafaela Carlier</li> <li>Production Assistant: Pamela Gallo</li> <li>Camera : Jacobo Sucari</li> <li>Drone Camera : Tomás Gasulla</li> <li>Ginbal Camera : Lucas Sucari Dunkel</li> <li>Direct sound recording: Irina Warner</li> <li>Interview recording control: Mireia Font</li> <li>Original music: Tom Johnson</li> <li>Digital sound creation: Jacobo Sucari</li> <li>Sound editing: Luca Rulo fidalgo</li> <li>Color editing: Natasha Ikoli</li> <li>Design / graphics: Esteban Hernández</li> <li>Assistant editor: Raquel García</li> <li>Translation texts German / French: Marion Tamme de Aquista</li> <li>Main characters : (in order of appearance) <ul> <li>Irina Warner</li> <li>Roger Rull</li> <li>Dominique Delpirou</li> <li>Denis Lavant</li> <li>Madeleine Claus</li> <li>Alexandre Cloud</li> <li>Lothar Eichhorn</li> <li>Siegfried Joseph</li> <li>Beat Röösli</li> <li>Alex Wix</li> <li>Michael Lowy</li> </ul> </li> <li>Running time: 57 minutes</li> <li>Production: Banyuls, Barcelona 2024.</li> </ul> <h2 id="jacobo-sucaris-biography">JACOBO SUCARI’S BIOGRAPHY</h2> <p>Born in Buenos Aires in 1958, I live in Barcelona.</p> <ul> <li>Professor of video and documentary processes at the Faculty of Fine Arts at the University of Barcelona (U.B.).</li> <li>Writer and musician.</li> <li>Doctorate from the University of Barcelona.</li> </ul> <h3 id="career-summary">CAREER SUMMARY:</h3> <p>Documentary filmmaker, musical improvisation instrumentalist and writer. PhD Professor at the Faculty of Fine Arts, University of Barcelona (UB). My creative work is based on the intersection of image, text and sound, constructed in a synchronic way, as an audiovisual composition. In my videography the narratives are often abstract or experimental; in others, closer to the documentary genre, the plot assumes a dramatic development. My work have been presented in different spaces and contexts, both in the artistic tradition such as museums and galleries, as well as in the cinematographic tradition: festivals, cinemas and programming in different TV channels.</p> <h3 id="studies">STUDIES:</h3> <ul> <li>Cinematography and television at the ‘University of Fine Arts’ Tel-Aviv, Israel’. 1977- 1979.</li> <li>Diploma in Information Sciences ‘Autonomous University of Barcelona. 1980-85</li> <li>Doctorate from the University of Barcelona with a thesis on ‘The expanded documentary’, screen and space’. 2009.</li> </ul> <h2 id="filmography">FILMOGRAPHY</h2> <ul> <li>LINA BO BARDI. FROM GLASS TO CLAY. Documentary. 43 min. 2021</li> <li>ISRAEL ON MY MIND. Documentary. 28 min. 2020.</li> <li>AKHA, AT THE BORDER. Documentary. 56 min. 2019.</li> <li>HOUSING LAW PAH. HEALTH AND HOUSING. Participatory documentary. 2017.</li> <li>MEMORY AND IDENTITY IN THE COMMUNITY OF SALITRE. Participatory documentary. 52 min. 2015</li> <li>THE DREAM OF HEROES. TV documentary. 56 min. 2013</li> <li>A DANCING COSMOS, SUFISM, MYSTICISM AND MUSIC. TV documentary, 54 min. 2011.</li> <li>DESTROY AND BUILD. THE STORY OF A FACTORY. TV documentary, 56 min. 2011.</li> <li>THE TRANSFORMED CITY. INSTALLATION. Expanded documentary. 2008.</li> <li>THE STRUGGLE FOR URBAN SPACE. TV documentary, 59 min. 2006-2007.</li> <li>ILLUSORY BEHAVIOUR. Installation. 2004.</li> <li>STORIES FROM THE PERIPHERY. TV documentary, 54 min. 2003.</li> <li>DISCIPLINE. INSTALLATION. Extended documentary. 2002-2003.</li> <li>PARALYSED, IN A STATE OF TERROR. Documentary, 47 min. 2001.</li> </ul> <h2 id="jacobo-sucari-artistic-cv">Jacobo Sucari ARTISTIC CV</h2> <h3 id="audiovisual-work-prizes">Audiovisual work prizes:</h3> <ul> <li>First prize for the thematic work ‘H2O’ for: ‘DES HISTOIRES DE LA PÉRIPHÉRIE’. Documentary. VAD Festival. Girona, Spain, 2007.</li> <li>VISIONES DE FUTURO- RETEVISIÓN’ award for artistic projects, for the installation project: ‘DISCIPLINA, SIN MEMORIA Y SIN PODER’. Barcelona, Spain, 2001.</li> <li>Special mention at the Festival of the Instituto de Cooperación Iberoamericana, for the video-creation ‘EL EFECTO KULESHOV’, Buenos Aires, Argentina, 2000.</li> <li>First prize at the Llivia-Estavar Video Festival, for ‘LA VENTANA (RELATO)’. France. 2000.</li> <li>Travelling exhibition - Video creation prize: ‘MUESTRA DE ARTE ELECTRÓNICO’. Generalitat de Catalunya. Spain, 2000.</li> <li>First Prize at the Navarre International Video Festival, Spain, for the creative documentary ‘REM, ESTUDIOS SOBRE EL COMPORTAMIENTO NOCTURNO’ (REM, STUDIES ON NIGHT BEHAVIOUR). Spain, 1998.</li> <li>Travelling exhibition prize: ART AND TECHNOLOGY. Generalitat de Catalunya. Spain, 1998.</li> </ul> <h3 id="books-and-dvds-publications-in-recent-years">Books and DVDs publications in recent years:</h3> <ul> <li>2022: ‘Technologies for the common good: from collective knowledge to community good’. (essay) 2021 - ‘Frustrated projects’ (fiction).</li> <li>2015 - 2021: Publication in specialist journals of various research works on art, science and technology (essay). https://jacobosucari.com/publications/</li> <li>2015: Distribution of the DVD in bookshops: DVD ‘Un cosmos qui danse, soufisme mystique et musique’. Documentary. 54 minutes.</li> <li>2014: Formes de l’imaginaire techno-esthétique. The cinema of thought. Editorial Aldea Global. Published by the University of Valencia, Spain (essay).</li> <li>2012: Le documentaire élargi, l’écran et l’espace. Editorial UOCPress (essay)</li> <li>2011: ‘The transformed city’. Two television documentaries and an installation on urban transformation: ‘The struggle for urban space’ and ‘Destroy and build, the story of a factory’. DVD. Caixaforum, TV3, and La Trinxera Audiovisual SCCL. <h2 id="expositions">Expositions:</h2> </li> <li>Barcelona Beat Sesion. Vídeo, poesia i música. Llibreria Calders. 2018.</li> <li>L’experiència col·lectiva. Exposició Vídeo. Virreina Centri de la Imatge. Comissari i autor. 2018.</li> <li>LEM. GTS. Projecte PAPF. Directe música-Vídeo. 2017.</li> <li>Flux. Festival Vídeo d’Autor. Projecte PAPF. 2017.</li> <li>ESPOL. Documental Participatiu. Guayaquil l’Equador. 2015.</li> <li>Casa de Cultura. Instal·lació La ciutat transformada .Girona. Espanya 2012.</li> <li>Istanbul international architecture and urban films. 2011</li> <li>MARQ. Societat d’Arquitectes. Instal·lació La ciutat transformada . BS AS. l’Argentina. 2011</li> <li>Espai-Ciutat: Instal·lació La ciutat transformada. 2010 Vitòria Gasteisz.</li> <li>Galeria MX10Espai. Vídeo-Art. La Contemplació. Loop 2010. Barcelona.</li> <li>Ecocinema. Videoart i Documental. Israel 2008.</li> <li>Vídeo i Arts Digitals. VAD. Girona 2007. Espanya.</li> <li>Habitar el Present. Nous Ministeris. Madrid 2007.</li> <li>Festival Internacional de Cinema de Conca, l’Equador. 2007</li> <li>Abastos. Mostra Cinematogràfica de l’Atlàntic. 2007</li> <li>XXIV Festival de cinema de Bogotà.2007.</li> <li>Festival Internacional de Cinema de Medi Ambient de Catalunya. 2007</li> <li>III Festival Internacional de Documentals 2007, Caracas Marató DocFestival</li> <li>Festival de Cinema de Màlaga, 2007.</li> <li>Fluxus. Vídeo d’Autor. Mediateca de Caixaforum. 2006. Espanya.</li> <li>“La Capella”. Instal·lació “La caiguda”. Barcelona, Espanya. 2005.</li> <li>Sala d’Art de Vic. Vic. 2005. - OVNI 2005. Mostra de vídeo. Barcelona, Espanya.</li> <li>Loop. Videoart. Barcelona 2004/2005. Espanya.</li> <li>Festival Internacional de Vídeo i Arts Digitals, VAD. Girona, 2004, España</li> <li>Cinema du Rèel. Festival França 2004.</li> <li>Galeria MXEspai. Cicle “Poètiques Polítiques”. Barcelona 2004.</li> <li>Festival Cinema du Réel. París. França, 2004.</li> <li>Festival Internacional de Cinema de Catalunya. Sitges, 2003.</li> <li>Festival de cinema L’Alternativa. Barcelona, 2003.</li> <li>Videozone. Israel, 2002.</li> <li>Videobrasil, 2001.</li> <li>Wide World Vídeo Festival. Amsterdam, 2000.</li> <li>“Monocanal”. Mostra Itineante del Museu d’Art Reina Sofia. Itinerant per set museus d’art contemporani a Espanya. 2003.</li> <li>Instal·lació Documental. “Disciplina, sense memòria i sense poder. La Capella. ICUB. Barcelona. Febrer- Abril 2003.</li> <li>Videozone. Col·lectiva de Videoart. Israel. 2002.</li> <li>Exposició sobre art a Llatinoamèrica, secció imatge “B&amp;N i de color”, en el Museu d’Art Reina Sofia. 2000-2001.</li> <li>Videobrasil. Colectiva de Videoart. 2001.</li> <li>MAMBA, Museu d’Art Modern de Buenos Aires, 2000. Projecció de treballs.</li> </ul> <blockquote> <p><strong>More info:</strong></p> <p>www.jacobosucari.com</p> <p><strong>Contact:</strong></p> <p>jacobosucari@gmail.com +34699385179 Barcelona 2025</p> </blockquote>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="walter-benjamin"/><category term="documentales"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Download technical specifications here (in English)]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Walter Benjamin, el aura del camino</title><link href="http://jacobosucari.com/blog/2025/homenaje-a-benjamin/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Walter Benjamin, el aura del camino"/><published>2025-05-05T11:59:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-05-05T11:59:00+00:00</updated><id>http://jacobosucari.com/blog/2025/homenaje-a-benjamin</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://jacobosucari.com/blog/2025/homenaje-a-benjamin/"><![CDATA[<p>Una película escrita y dirigida per Jacobo Sucari.</p> <p>Information in English can be downloaded <a href="/assets/pdf/walter-benjamin.pdf">here</a>, and the post in English can be seen <a href="http://jacobosucari.com/blog/2025/walter-benjamin-in-english/">here</a></p> <h2 id="sinopsis">Sinopsis</h2> <p>El filósofo Walter Benjamin intentó huir del avance nazi en 1940 cruzando a pie la frontera entre Francia y España. Su huida acabó en suicidio. La ruta que siguió entre Banyuls y Portbou ha sido bautizada desde entonces como el Camino de Walter Benjamin, y es recorrida cada año por cientos de peregrinos que acuden para honrar su memoria junto a la de otros exilios: el del bando republicano tras el golpe franquista en España, la de tantos huyendo de la barbarie Nazi en la Segunda Guerra. El documental “Walter Benjamin, el aura del camino” es la historia de esta ruta, relato de memoria histórica, una reflexión sobre el exilio y el pensamiento de Benjamin.</p> <iframe src="https://player.vimeo.com/video/954134740" width="700" height="480" frameborder="0" webkitallowfullscreen="" mozallowfullscreen="" allowfullscreen=""> </iframe>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="walter-benjamin"/><category term="documentales"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Una película escrita y dirigida per Jacobo Sucari.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Documental: Lina Bo Bardi: del vidrio al barro</title><link href="http://jacobosucari.com/blog/2022/lina-bo-bardi/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Documental: Lina Bo Bardi: del vidrio al barro"/><published>2022-12-28T21:01:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-12-28T21:01:00+00:00</updated><id>http://jacobosucari.com/blog/2022/lina-bo-bardi</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://jacobosucari.com/blog/2022/lina-bo-bardi/"><![CDATA[<h3 id="sinopsis">Sinopsis.</h3> <p>Una joven arquitecta en Brasil, venida de la Italia de postguerra.</p> <p>Lina Bo Bardi formó parte de la modernidad, del desarrollismo a la brasilera que en el Sao Paulo de los años 50 imprimió un nuevo carácter a la arquitectura.</p> <p>Pero Lina fue mucho más lejos que este reflejo de la modernidad europea. La convivencia y estancia en los sitios donde desarrolló sus proyectos, la observación del territorio, las gentes y la cultura popular, el intercambio democrático del conocimiento –un diálogo entre iguales- le llevó a imprimir una mirada antropológica a su arquitectura.</p> <div class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge"><div class="highlight"><pre class="highlight"><code>FICHA TÉCNICA:
Documental: Lina Bo Bardi, del vidrio al barro.
Duración: 43 minutos.
Dirección: Josep Maria Montaner y Jacobo Sucari.

Con la participación de los arquitectos: 
Renato Anelli, Paulo Mendes da Rocha, Paulo Bruna, Anna Ramos, Mara Sanchez Llorens.
 
Realización, cámara y guion: Jacobo Sucari
Texto y guion: Josep Mº Montaner
Música: Mestres Quadreny
Edición: Irina Warner, Jacobo Sucari.
Renders en 3D: Juan Luis Campoy.
Posproducción de Sonido: Lucca Rullo.
Cámaras en plató: German Regueira, Lucia Castro Álvarez, Èlia Fort. Gianluca Ritucci. Lucas Sucari.
Diseño cartel: Tito Inchaurralde
Producción: Asociación Multimedia de Acciones Culturales.
Con la Colaboración de: 
el Istituto Italiano di Cultura in Spagna; 
el COAC: Col·legi d’Arquitectes de Barcelona, Arquitectes. Cat; 
la Facultad de Belles Arts, Universitat de Barcelona, LabMedia del Departament de Imatge i Arts Visuals de Belles Arts;
el Instituto Lina Bo y Pietro Bardi, de Sao Paulo.
Año de producción: Barcelona, 2021-2022.
VimeoId: 631378495

</code></pre></div></div> <h2 id="documentary-film-lina-bo-bardi-from-glass-to-mud">DOCUMENTARY FILM: LINA BO BARDI, FROM GLASS TO MUD.</h2> <h3 id="synopsis">Synopsis.</h3> <p>A young architect in Brazil, coming from post-war Italy. Lina Bo Bardi was part of modernity, of Brazilian-style developmentalism who in Sao Paulo in the 1950s imprinted a new character on architecture. But Lina went much further than this reflection of European modernity. The coexistence and and stay in the places where she developed her projects, the observation of the territory, the people and popular culture, the democratic exchange of knowledge -a dialogue between equals- led her to print an anthropological look at her architecture.</p> <div class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge"><div class="highlight"><pre class="highlight"><code>TECHNICAL SPECIFICATION:

Documentary: Lina Bo Bardi, from glass to clay. 
Duration: 43 minutes. 
Direction: Josep Maria Montaner and Jacobo Sucari. 
With the participation of the architects: Renato Anelli, Paulo Mendes da Rocha, Paulo Bruna, Anna Ramos, Mara Sanchez Llorens. 
Director, camera and script: Jacobo Sucari 
Text and script: Josep Mº Montaner 
Music: Mestres Quadreny 
Edition: Irina Warner, Jacobo Sucari. 
3D renderings: Juan Luis Campoy. 
Sound Postproduction: Lucca Rullo. 
Cameras on set: German Regueira, Lucia Castro Álvarez, Èlia Fort. Gianluca Ritucci. Lucas Sucari. 
Poster design: Tito Inchaurralde 
Production: Multimedia Association of Cultural Actions. 
In collaboration with: the Italian Institute of Culture in Spain; the COAC: Col·legi d'Arquitectes de Barcelona, Arquitectes. cat; the Faculty of Fine Arts, University of Barcelona, LabMedia of the Department of Imaging and Visual Arts of Fine Arts; the Lina Bo and Pietro Bardi Institute, in São Paulo.
Year of production: Barcelona, 2021-2022.
</code></pre></div></div>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="documentales"/><category term="lina-bo-bardi"/><category term="arquitectura"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Una joven arquitecta en Brasil, venida de la Italia de postguerra]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Israel on my mind</title><link href="http://jacobosucari.com/blog/2022/israel-on-my-mind/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Israel on my mind"/><published>2022-11-04T17:39:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-11-04T17:39:00+00:00</updated><id>http://jacobosucari.com/blog/2022/israel-on-my-mind</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://jacobosucari.com/blog/2022/israel-on-my-mind/"><![CDATA[<h2 id="imaginary-journeys-nº-3">Imaginary journeys nº 3.</h2> <h3 id="sinopsis">Sinopsis.</h3> <p>Israel on my mind is a film that explores the past, present and future of Israel. A territory at war for more than seventy years, and in the midst of a very complex local situation. Two Israeli citizens tell us about their anchorage in this land of burning intensity and harsh illumination.</p> <p>Israel on my mind is the third chapter of the “Imaginary Journeys”, a series of audiovisual anthropological investigations that move through territories that ask to be discovered through the language of their inhabitants: construction of a story between history, their social imaginaries and their speakers.</p> <div class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge"><div class="highlight"><pre class="highlight"><code>Technical sheet:

A film by Jacobo Sucari
Recording and editing by Jacobo Sucari
With the participation of Lance Hunter and Yoav Loch.
Lenght: 28:30 min.
Israel – Barcelona: 2018 – 2020.
@creative comun
</code></pre></div></div> <h2 id="viajes-imaginarios-nº-3">Viajes imaginarios nº 3.</h2> <h3 id="sinopsis-1">Sinopsis.</h3> <p><em>Israel on my mind</em> <del>es</del> una película que indaga sobre el pasado, el presente y el futuro de Israel. Un territorio sumido en guerra desde hace más de setenta años, y en medio de una coyuntura local muy compleja. Dos ciudadanos israelíes nos relatan su anclaje en esta tierra de ardiente intensidad e iluminaciones desbastadoras.</p> <p><em>Israel on my mind</em> es el tercer capítulo de los “Viajes imaginarios”, una serie de indagación antropológica de carácter audiovisual que se mueve por territorios que piden ser descubiertos a través del lenguaje de sus habitantes: construcción de un relato entre la historia, sus imaginarios sociales y sus hablantes.</p> <div class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge"><div class="highlight"><pre class="highlight"><code>Ficha técnica:
Una película de Jacobo Sucari.
Grabación y edición de Jacobo Sucari
Con la participación de Lance Hunter y Yoav Loch.
Duración: 28:30 min.
Israel - Barcelona: 2018 - 2020.
@creative comun
</code></pre></div></div>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="israel"/><category term="documentales"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Israel on my mind es una película que indaga sobre el pasado, el presente y el futuro de Israel. Un territorio sumido en guerra desde hace más de setenta años, y en medio de una coyuntura local muy compleja. Dos ciudadanos israelíes nos relatan su anclaje en esta tierra de ardiente intensidad e iluminaciones desbastadoras.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Tecnologías para el bien común</title><link href="http://jacobosucari.com/blog/2022/tecnologias-para-el-bien-comun/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Tecnologías para el bien común"/><published>2022-08-01T11:59:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-08-01T11:59:00+00:00</updated><id>http://jacobosucari.com/blog/2022/tecnologias-para-el-bien-comun</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://jacobosucari.com/blog/2022/tecnologias-para-el-bien-comun/"><![CDATA[<div class="container"> <div class="row"> <div class="col-sm"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" media="(max-width: 480px)" srcset="/assets/pdf/tecnologias_para_el_bien_comun-480.webp"/> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" media="(max-width: 800px)" srcset="/assets/pdf/tecnologias_para_el_bien_comun-800.webp"/> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" media="(max-width: 1400px)" srcset="/assets/pdf/tecnologias_para_el_bien_comun-1400.webp"/> <img src="/assets/pdf/tecnologias_para_el_bien_comun.jpg" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="auto" height="auto" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> <div class="col-sm"> Las tecnologías pueden ser nuestro veneno o nuestro pharmakon, es decir el antídoto que el veneno implantado en el tejido social de la producción, necesita. El trabajo en redes, el pensamiento colaborativo, la idea de un procomún en oposición a aquello privado y en manos de élites que defienden unos intereses que van en contra del sentido del común, se manifiesta como un polo de acción con una capacidad de subversión en todas las esferas de la convivencia que denota una praxis del cambio en acción. Ya no se trata de movimientos sociales para tejer utopías de futuro, sino modos de la convivencia presente capaces de variar el conjunto de la producción. *Tecnologías para el bien común. Del saber colectivo a la expansión comunitaria* sigue una línea de investigación vinculada a la arqueología mediática en la irrenunciable conexión entre tecnología y política. </div> </div> </div> <p><strong>Ver el libro <a href="https://www.p21.es/libro/tecnologias-para-el-bien-comun/">en la web de la editorial</a></strong></p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="publicaciones"/><category term="narrativa"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Las tecnologías pueden ser nuestro veneno o nuestro pharmakon, es decir el antídoto que el veneno implantado en el tejido social de la producción, necesita. El trabajo en redes, el pensamiento colaborativo, la idea de un procomún en oposición a aquello privado y en manos de élites que defienden unos intereses que van en contra del sentido del común, se manifiesta como un polo de acción con una capacidad de subversión en todas las esferas de la convivencia que denota una praxis del cambio en acción. Ya no se trata de movimientos sociales para tejer utopías de futuro, sino modos de la convivencia presente capaces de variar el conjunto de la producción. “Tecnologías para el bien común. Del saber colectivo a la expansión comunitaria” sigue una línea de investigación vinculada a la arqueología mediática en la irrenunciable conexión entre tecnología y política.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Los proyectos frustrados</title><link href="http://jacobosucari.com/blog/2022/los-proyectos-frustrados/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Los proyectos frustrados"/><published>2022-05-01T04:59:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-05-01T04:59:00+00:00</updated><id>http://jacobosucari.com/blog/2022/los-proyectos-frustrados</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://jacobosucari.com/blog/2022/los-proyectos-frustrados/"><![CDATA[<div class="container"> <div class="row"> <div class="col-sm"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" media="(max-width: 480px)" srcset="/assets/pdf/proyectos_frustrados-480.webp"/> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" media="(max-width: 800px)" srcset="/assets/pdf/proyectos_frustrados-800.webp"/> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" media="(max-width: 1400px)" srcset="/assets/pdf/proyectos_frustrados-1400.webp"/> <img src="/assets/pdf/proyectos_frustrados.jpg" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="auto" height="auto" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> <div class="col-sm"> El libro «Los proyectos frustrados» presenta cuatro historias que nos trasladan de Beit-El en Israel, a Bucarest vía Barcelona, cruza Buenos Aires, y nos devuelve a una Barcelona en el apogeo del turismo de masas. Cuatro relatos intensos en que documental y ficción se anudan y tejen historias que forman parte de la vida entendida como forma narrativa. </div> </div> </div> <p><strong>Ver el libro <a href="https://www.p21.es/libro/los-proyectos-frustrados/">en la web de la editorial</a></strong></p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="publicaciones"/><category term="narrativa"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[El libro “Los proyectos frustrados” presenta cuatro historias que nos trasladan de Beit-El en Israel, a Bucarest vía Barcelona, cruza Buenos Aires, y nos devuelve a una Barcelona en el apogeo del turismo de masas. Cuatro relatos intensos en que documental y ficción se anudan y tejen historias que forman parte de la vida entendida como forma narrativa.]]></summary></entry></feed>